ha the the
公顷的
the norm
规范
well
好
the I'm out oppenheim
在我出奥本海姆
and I'd like to welcome you to this video tape course on signals and systems
我想欢迎您到这个录像带课程，信号与系统
signals at least
信号中的至少
as an informal definition are functions
作为一个非正式的定义是函数
one or more independent variables that
一个或一个以上独立变量
typically carry some type information systems in
通常携带某种类型的信息系统
are setting with typically be used the process signals
正在设置与通常使用的过程信号
one very common example of a signal
一个信号的一个很常见的例子
might be let's say speech signal and you might think
可能是我们说的语音信号，你可能会认为
love the air pressure as a function of time
爱的空气压力作为时间的函数
or perhaps the electrical signal effort goes through the microphone
或者该电信号的努力去通过麦克风
transducer is a function of time as representing the speech signal
换能器的时间作为代表语音信号的一个函数
and we might see a typical speech signal
我们可能会看到一个典型的语音信号
looking something like i've indicated here
看着像我在这里表示
its a function time
其功能的时间
in this particular case and the independent variable
在这种特殊情况下，并自变量
being time is in fact continuous
即时间实际上是连续
and so a signal like this we will typically be referring to
所以像这样的信号，我们通常是指
as a continuous-time signals now
因为现在是一个连续时间信号
it also for this particular example is a function
它也为这个特定的例子是一个函数
one independent variable and
一个自变量和
that will be referred to as
这将被称为
the one dimensional signal
一维信号
corresponding to the fact that there's only
对应于该事实，即只有
one independent variable several independent variables
一个自变量几个独立变量
so the speech signal is an example
这样的语音信号是一个例子
a continuous-time one-dimensional signal
连续时间的一维信号
now signals can of course
现在信号当然可以
be multi-dimensional and they may not have as their independent variables time
是多维的，他们可能没有为自己的独立变量时间
variables
变量
one very common example are
一个非常常见的例子是
the examples represented by images images
通过图像图像表示的例子
as signals we might think I'll as
作为信号我们可能会认为我会为
representing brightness as it varies
代表亮度，因为它变化
in a horizontal and vertical
在水平和垂直
direction and so the brightness as a function
方向等的亮度作为函数
these two spatial variables is then
这两个空间变量，然后
a two-dimensional signal and
一个两维信号和
it the independent variables
它的自变量
would typically be continuous but of course they're not time variables
通常是连续的，但当然他们不是时间变量
and incidently it's worth
顺便说一句和它的价值
just commenting very often simply for convenience
只是注释，很多时候只是为了方便
will have a tendency to refer to the independent variables when we talk about
将有一种倾向，指的是自变量，当我们谈论
signals
信号
as time variables whether or not the really represent time
随着时间的变量是否真正代表时间
well let me illustrate
好让我举例说明
one example all image and
一个例子所有的图像和
this is a picture jpg for EA
这是一个JPG格式的图片为EA
who perhaps more than anyone else
也许谁比谁更
is responsible for the elegance and beauty
负责的优雅和美丽
a lot of the concepts we'll be talking about throughout this course
很多的概念我们将在本课程谈论
and when you look at this in addition to
当你看这除了
c4a himself you should recognize that what you're looking at
C4A自己，你应该明白，你在看什么
is basically a signal which is brightness as a function
基本上是一个信号，该信号是亮度的函数
the horizontal and vertical spatial variables
在水平和垂直空间变量
as another example
作为另一个例子
an image as a signal let's look at an aerial photograph
一个图像作为一个信号让我们来看看航拍照片
this is an aerial photograph taken
这是拍摄航空照片
over a setter roads which
在一个setter的道路
you can more less recognized in the picture and
你可以在画面更加减去已确认和
wanted the difficulties with this signal is that it
想与该信号的困难是，它
the road system is somewhat obscured by cloud cover
道路系统是由云层有点模糊
and well wanna show later
并且还有想告诉以后
as an example what a system
作为一个例子什么系统
might do to such as signal in terms of processing is an attempt to
可能会做诸如信号处理方面是企图
at least compensate some way for the
至少一些补偿方式为
cloud cover represented in the photograph following terms a
照片中的代表云层以下条款
the detailed analysis we go through during the course are
我们的过程中，都要经过详细的分析是
focus of attention is pretty much restricted to
关注的焦点是几乎仅限于
one-dimensional signals in fact we will be using
我们将使用实际上一维信号
two-dimensional signals more specifically images
二维信号的更具体的图像
very often to illustrate a variety
经常来说明各种
concepts now
现在概念
speech in images are examples
讲话图像的例子
what we refer to as continuous-time signals
我们称之为连续时间信号
in that they are functions
在它们的功能
continuous variables equally
连续变量同样
important classes signals will be concentrating on
重要的类信号将集中在
in the cores are signals are
在内核信号
discrete-time signals
离散时间信号
where by discrete-time we mean
其中由离散时间我们的意思
is that the signal is
是该信号是
a function integer variable
功能整型变量
and so specifically only takes on values
所以专门只对值
at in nature values the argument
在自然价值的说法
so here is a graphical illustration
所以这里是一个曲线示意图
the discrete-time signal and discrete-time signals arise
离散时间信号与离散时间信号出现
in a variety of ways one very common example
在各种不同的方式1非常常见的例子
it seems fairly often is discrete-time signals in the context
它似乎相当经常是离散时间信号中的上下文
economic time series and for example stock market analysis
经济时间序列和例如股票行情分析
so what I show here is one
所以我在这里展示的是
very commonly occurring example the discrete-time signal
非常普遍发生的示例的离散时间信号
it represents the weekly stock market index
它代表了每周股市指数
the independent variable in this case is
在这种情况下，自变量是
the week number and we see what the
的周数，我们看到了什么
stock market is doing over this particular period
做股票在这个特殊的时期
as a function or the number of the week and
作为一个功能或周数和
course along the vertical axis is the
当然沿着垂直轴是
weekly index incidently
每周顺便说一句指数
this particular period was not chosen
这个特殊的时期没有选择
random in fact captures very interesting aspect
随机事实上捕捉非常有趣的方面
stock market history namely the
股市历史即
stock market crash in 1929
股市崩盘，1929年
which in fact is represented by behavior
这实际上是由行为代表
this discrete time signal or sequence
这种离散时间信号或序列
in this particular area so this dramatic dip in fact
在这方面，其实这样这个戏剧性的浸
is the stock market crash 1929
是股市大跌1929
well the dow jones weekly average is an example
以及道琼斯周平均就是一个例子
all a one-dimensional discrete-time signal
所有一维离散时间信号
and just as with continuous time
而就像连续时间
we had not just one-dimensional multi-dimensional signals
我们有不只是一维的多维信号
likewise we have multi-dimensional signals
同样我们有多维信号
in the discrete-time case where
在离散时间情况下
in that case then the discrete-time signal that we're talking about a
在这种情况下，那么，我们谈论的是一个离散时间信号
sequence
序列
is a function love to integer variables
是一个函数爱整型变量
and is one example this might let's say represent a spatial
并且是一个例子，这可能让我们说代表了空间
antenna array where this is
天线阵列中，这是
array number in let's say the horizontal
在假设的水平阵列数
direction and this is array number in the vertical direction
方向和垂直方向这是序列号
both classes signals continuous-time and discrete-time
这两类信号的连续时间和离散时间
as i've indicated are very important and it should be emphasized
因为我已经表明是非常重要的，它应该强调
dead the importance I'll discrete-time signals associated processing
死者的重要性，我会离散时间信号相关的处理
continues to grow in large part because
持续增长在很大程度上是因为
I'll the current and emerging technologies
我将在当前和新兴技术
that permit basically the processing
该许可证的基本处理
or continuous-time signals by
通过或连续时间信号
first converting to discrete-time signals
第一转换为离散时间信号
and processing them with discrete time systems
并处理它们与离散时间系统
and that in fact is a topic that we will
那其实是一个话题，我们将
discuss in a fair manner detail later on in the course
以公平的方式详细后来在讨论过程
let's now turn our attention to systems
现在让我们把注意力转向系统
and as they indicated a system
当他们表示系统
basically processes signals
基本的信号处理
and they have of course inputs
他们有当然的投入
and outputs and depending on
和输出，这取决于
whether we're talking about continuous-time for discrete-time
无论我们谈论的连续时间的离散时间
the system maybe a continuous-time system
该系统可能是连续时间系统
or a discrete-time system so in the continuous-time
或离散时间系统，以便在连续时间
case I indicate here in input: accept T
情况下，我在此表明在输入：接受Ŧ
and an output y ft if we were talking
和一个输出y英尺，如果我们谈论
about discrete-time system I would represent
关于离散时间系统我会代表
the the input in terms a discrete-time
的输入条件中一个离散时间
variable and of course the output interns a
变量和过程的输出实习生
discrete-time variable also
离散时间变量也
now in very general terms systems are hard to deal with
现在非常笼统系统是很难对付
because is they are defined very broadly a very generally
因为被他们定义非常广泛非常普遍
and in dealing with systems and analyzing
和在处理系统和分析
what we will do is attempt to exploit
我们将要做的是尝试利用
some very specific and as we'll see
一些非常具体的，正如我们将看到
very useful system properties
非常有用的系统性能
to indicate what I mean and how things might be split up
以表明我的意思和事情如何可能被分拆
we could talk about systems and we'll talk about systems
我们可以谈论系统，我们将讨论系统
that are linear and we could
是线性的，我们可以
divide systems basically into systems that are either linear
分割系统基本上成，要么线性系统
or nonlinear and we will
或非线性的，我们将
or and also devices turns into systems that are
或者，也装置变成是系统
what we refer to as time-invariant
我们称之为时间不变
or time-varying systems and these aren't turns that
或时变系统和这些都不是原来的
we've defined yet of course but we will be defining
我们尚未定义，当然，但我们将定义
in the course very shortly and while
在使用过程很快，虽然
in some sense this division represents all systems and this those two
在某种意义上，这个师代表所有的系统，这这两个
the focus of the course is really going to be principally
本课程的重点是真的要成为主要
on linear time-invariant systems
线性时不变系统
so in its basically the system's
所以在其基本系统的
that we will be focusing on and
我们将专注于与
will be referring to those systems as linear
将参照这些系统为线性
time-invariant systems
时不变系统
well as a free clip said some other kinds of things that systems can do
以及免费的夹子说，一些其他种类的东西，系统可以做
let me illustrate first in
让我先说明
I a one-dimensional continuous-time
余的一维连续时间
context and then later with a discrete-time example
上下文，然后后用一个离散时间的例子
one example I'll some processing
一个例子，我将一些处理
I'll signals with an appropriate system
我将信号与一个合适的制度
the particular example that I want to illustrate
我想说明的特定示例中
relates to the restoration or old recordings
涉及恢复或老录音
and missus some work that was done by Professor Thomas stocker who
和太太，是由教授托马斯收容器做了一些工作，谁
is at the University Utah and work that he had done a number of years ago
是在犹他大学和工作，他已经做了若干年前
relating to the fact day in all recordings
有关事实在一天的所有记录
for example in caruso recordings
例如，在卡鲁索录音
the recording was done through mechanical morning
录音是通过机械上午完成
and the characteristics love the horn tended to vary from day to day
和特性爱喇叭倾向于改变每一天
and because if the characteristics of the horn
并且，因为如果喇叭的特征
the recording tended to have a muffled quality something like
录音往往有一个低沉的品质像
yes sorta the sense that you would get
是八九不离十的感觉，你会得到
if you were speaking through a megaphone
如果你是通过扩音器说
what professor stock and it was developed a system
教授什么股票和它开发了一个系统
to process these old recordings
处理这些老录音
in such a way dead a lot or
以这样的方式死了很多或
the characteristics and distortion do
的特性和失真做
to that recording system was removed so I'd like to
到被删除的记录系统，所以我想
illustrate that as one example some signal processing with an appropriate
说明，作为一个例子用适当的一些信号处理
continuous-time system and what you'll hear
连续时间系统和你会听到
is a to track recording
是跟踪记录
on the first track is the original on restored
在第一轨道是恢复了原来的
caruso recording and on the second track
卡鲁索记录和第二记录道
is the result of the restoration and so as I switch back and forth
是恢复的效果，因此，我来​​回切换
from channel one to channel two will be switching from
从通道一个通道两人将来自被切换
the original to the restored will begin the tape
原来的恢复将开始磁带
by playing the original and
玩原件及
day and as it proceeds will switch
一天，因为它的收益就会切换
so we begin on channel one
所以我们开始通道一
low pS The Regent
低PS丽晶酒店
switch now process middle
现在切换过程中间
him home
他回家
his back 0 hit
他回0命中
back to the original p
返回到原来的对
I read
我读
back to the restoration
回复
mine yard
矿堆场
home
家
and once again back to the rigid
并再次回到刚性
mid
中
and presumably and hopefully what you heard
想必，希望你听到
was dead in the restoration in fact a lot of the muffled
死在事实上恢复了很多的闷响
characteristics the original recording
特色的原始录音
were compensated for or remove now
对于被补偿或者现在删除
one of the interesting things that happened in fact in the work that
的发生，其实在工作中有趣的事情之一
lesser Stockham did is that in the process of the restoration and perhaps
小Stockham确实是在恢复的过程中，也许
you've heard this
你听说过这个
in the process of the restoration in fact some other background noise on the
在实际上恢复过程的一些其他背景噪音
recording
记录
was emphasize and so he processed
被强调，所以他处理
this the signal further in an attempt to
这在尝试将信号进一步
remove that background noise and with that particular processing the
去除背景噪声，并与特定的处理
processing
处理
was very highly nonlinear a very interesting thing happened
很是高度非线性的一个非常有趣的事情发生了
which was that not only in at processing
这是不仅在加工时
was the background noise removal but somewhat surprisingly
是背景噪声去除，但有些令人惊讶
also the orchestra was and let me just plain bad
还乐团是，让我只是普通的坏
now as an example love some very sophisticated processing
现在作为一个例子喜欢一些很复杂的处理
with the nonlinear system what you'll hear on channel one
与非线性系统，你会听到通道一什么
0 is the restoration as
0是恢复为
we just plated when I switch to chat
我们只是镀当我切换到聊天
to will the Hampton
以将在汉普顿
processing him home
处理他回家
and acted one now
并担任一个吧
0 would im
0会即时通讯
hell
地狱
now inside
现在里面
back
后面
why did
何必当初
well
好
him
他
finally once again world
终于又一次世界
okay so
好了，
that's an example love processing Ave
这是一个例子爱情加工大道
continuous-time signal with a corresponding continuous-time
与相应的连续时间的连续时间信号
system now I'd like to illustrate an example
系统现在我想说明一个例子
some processing discrete-time signal and I'd like to do that in the context that
一些处理离散时间信号，我想这样做的背景下，
the example
该示例
ratio before a discrete-time signal which was
这是一个离散时间信号之前比
the dow jones industrial weekly stock market index
道琼斯工业周刊股市指数
I head shown it before as
我以前作为顶头表明，它
I've shown it here again over a period
我已经过了一段显示在这里再次
of slightly more than a year where this
比去年略多，其中这
is the number of weeks and this is the
是的周数，这是
weekly index and to illustrate
每周指数和说明
some of the processing what I'd like to do
一些我想要做的处理
is show the stock market index
是显示股市指数
weekly index over a much longer time period a particular
每周指数在更长的时间内某一特定
the weekly index over a ten year period
每周指数在十年内
and that's what I show here so
这就是我在这里展示等等
what this covers is roughly 1927
这是什么占地面积大约是1927年
to 1937 and
到1937年，
in this case although this is still a discrete-time signal
在这种情况下，尽管这仍然是一个离散时间信号
just simply for the purposes display what we've done
只是单纯的目的，显示我们做了什么
is to essentially connect the dots and
为从根本上连接点和
draw continuous curve through the points so that this picture isn't filled up
通过点画出连续的曲线，使这幅画是不是充满了
with a lot of vertical lines
有很多的垂直线
so this is the discrete-time sequence
所以这是离散时间序列
represents the weekly Dow Jones
代表每周道琼斯
Dow Jones index over a 10-year period and
道琼斯指数在10年的时间和
here by the way again is the crash of
这里顺便说又是坠毁
it's interesting to note by the way day
这是有趣的一天的方式
actually the disaster in the stock market wasn't so much the 1929 crash
实际上在股市的灾难是没有这么多的1929年崩溃
but the long downward trend that follow that and you can see that here
但长期下降趋势遵循这一点，你可以看到，这里
by kinda filtering through by I
通过还挺通过我过滤
the rapid variations in the index and what you see is this
在索引中，你看到了什么变化迅速这是
smooth downward trend followed
平滑下降的趋势跟随
eventually by upward trend now
最终被上升的趋势现在
this issue love looking at something like this looking at a sequence
这个问题喜欢看这样的事情在看一个序列
and following the smoother parts if it namely
和以下的平滑的部分，如果它即
the long-term trends is in fact something
长期趋势其实东西
that is done quite typically with economic time series like this
这是与经济时间序列这样做得比较典型的
and in particular what's done is to smooth it
特别是什么做的是它光滑
or average over some time period
或平均超过一定时间段
to emphasize the slow variations and de-emphasize the rapid variations
要强调的缓慢变化和贬低的迅速变化
and that in fact is processing that is done
并且，实际上是加工完成
with discrete-time system solos when you hear referred to let's say
与当听到简称假设离散时间系统的独奏
in stock market reports fifty one day moving average
在股市报告51天均线
that in fact is processing the stock market index
这实际上是处理股市指数
with a particular discrete-time system the result
与一个特定的离散时间系统的结果
up doing that on this particular example
这样做了，在这个特殊的例子
generates a smooth version the curve which I overly here
产生一个平滑的版本的曲线，我在这里过度
and the overlay
和覆盖
than is really attempting to track the
不是真的试图追踪
smoother variations and deemphasized
平滑的变化和去加重
more rapid variations let me just
更快速的变化让我
slightly offset that so that the different stands out a little more
稍微偏移，使不同的突出一点
and so here you see what is
所以在这里你看到的是什么
the original weekly index and
原周指数和
this is the result processing that sequence
这是该序列的处理结果
with inappropriate system
用不恰当的系统
to apply smoothing and in fact
应用平滑和实际上
what it is is a moving average and so here again
它是什么是移动平均线，所以在这里再次
you can see the in the smooth occurred
你可以看到在光滑的发生
this general downward trend
这个一般呈下降趋势
up until this time period followed by eventually
直到这个时间段之后，最终
recovery I well we've seen
恢复我很好，我们已经看到
example with a continuous-time signals
例如用一个连续时间信号
caruso recording an example with the discrete-time signal
卡鲁索记录的例子与离散时间信号
this stock market index and what I'd also like to show
此股票大盘指数，什么我也想展示
is 30 example which is
是30的例子是
the result some processing on an image in particular
其结果，尤其在图像上的一些处理
the image that we talked about before which was the aerial photographs
我们之前谈到的图像是空中拍摄的照片
that had the problem some cloud cover
这有一些问题云层
so once again what we see here
所以再次我们在这里看到的
is the original aerial photograph
是原来的航空照片
with the cloud cover and
与云量和
some processing was applied to this using a system
一些加工被施加到该一个使用系统
which in fact was both nonlinear
这实际上是两个非线性
and quote time-varying or in the case
和报价时间变化或情况
these independent variables would refer to it as spatially varying
这些独立变量将引用它作为空间变化
and the result applying that processing
其结果应用该处理
is shown in the joining
所示的接合
picture and what we see the air is
图片和我们所看到的是空气
hopefully a reasonable attempt
希望在合理的尝试
to compensate for the cloud cover and
以补偿云层和
this by the way was some work was done by Professor
这样的方式被一些工作是由教授做
them MIT and has been
他们麻省理工学院和已
very successful type processing were
非常成功的类型分别处理
aerial photographs I should say also
空中拍摄的照片我也要说
that this particular example is one where although the original signal
这个特定的例子是其中虽然对原始信号
was a signal dead is continuous time that is
是一个信号，死是连续的时间是
the independent variables are continuous as they are in a spatial
独立变量是连续的，因为它们是在空间
aerial photograph in fact for the processing
航空照片实际上为加工
that picture was first converted to a sequence
该图象首先被转换为一个序列
through a process called sampling which will be talking about later
通过这个过程被称为采样稍后将谈论
and then the processing in fact was done on a digital computer
然后实际上该处理在数字计算机上被做
okay well these then are some examples
还好以及这些然后是一些例子
all the use I'll some
全部使用我会一些
systems to process
系统处理
some signals both in continuous-time
无论是在连续时间的一些信号
in discrete-time for one-dimensional signals
在离散时间为一维信号
and for multi-dimensional signals
和多维信号
and as I kinda refer to systems we've
和我还挺指我们已经系统
thought of them as kinda one big block with appropriate
认为他们会用适当的还挺一大块
or associated input and output and
或相关联的输入和输出，并
as will be getting into in the first part of the course
如将要进入的过程的第一部分
very often systems are interconnected together
很多时候系统相互连接在一起
for a variety of reasons some other kinds of interconnections that will talk
适用于各种原因，某些其他类型的互连，将谈
about
关于
are connecting systems
正在连接系统
in what are called series are cascaded connections
在所谓的一系列级联连接
parallel interconnections feedback
并行互连反馈
interconnections and feedback interconnections
互连和反馈互连
in fact are very interesting very important
其实是很有趣很重要
for useful and will be major topic
有用的，将是重大课题
toward the end of the course feedback
对课程的反馈月底
as you may or may not know
因为您可能会或可能不知道
comes into play in a variety of situations
进场时在各种情况下
for example an amplifier design is we'll talk about
例如一个放大器的设计是我们将讨论
the black feedback plays an important role
黑色的反馈中起着重要作用
in a situation where you have
在一个情况下，你有
a basically unstable system feedback is often used to stabilize the system
一个基本上是不稳定的系统反馈通常被用来使系统稳定
and feedback interconnections systems in that sense
和反馈互连的系统在这个意义上
are very often used in high-performance aircraft
很多时候在高性能飞机上使用
which are inherently unstable and are stabilized
这本质上是不稳定的，是稳定的
this kind in action
这种在行动
just two give you a little sense this
只是两个给你一点感觉这
without going into any of the details
无需进入任何细节
what i'd like to show you is and excerpt
我想告诉你的是，并摘录
from a lecture day
从当天的演讲
we'll be seeing toward the end of the course relating to
我们将看到对课程的有关结束
feedback analysis a feedback systems and uses a feedback
反馈分析反馈系统，并使用反馈
and this is in the context what's referred to
这是在上下文中发生了什么被称为
as the inverted pendulum which is
作为倒立摆是
system that's basically unstable feedback
系统基本上是不稳定的反馈
interconnections are used to stabilize the idea
互连用于稳定主意
as you'll see in this brief clip is that
您将在这个简短的片段看到的是，
there is a cart that's moving on a track
有一种车是在动的轨道上
with a ride its pivoted at the base
用它搭在旋转底座
and so that system in the absence anything
并且使系统在不存在任何
is unstable in that the ride attend for
是不稳定的，该搭出席
and as we going to in detail in the lecture
当我们要在详细的演讲
later use feedback to
以后使用反馈
position the card under the pendulum to balance it
定位摆下的卡来平衡它
and in fact that balancing can be done even
而事实上该平衡甚至可以做
when we modify the system in a variety of ways
当我们修改了系统在各种不同的方式
as you'll see in this clip so let's take a look at that
您将在这个剪辑看到让我们来看看这
remembering that this is just a brief excerpt
记住，这只是一个简短的摘录
from a longer discussion I can change the
从一个较长的讨论中，我可以改变
overall system even further by
整个系统甚至进一步
let's say for example pouring a liquid
比方说，例如浇液体
and now let me also comment that
现在让我也评论说，
change the physics of a little bit because the
改变一点点的物理，因为
the liquid can slash around a little bit comes a little more complicated
液体可绕一点点的斜线来有点复杂
system but as you can see it still
系统，但你仍然可以看到它
remains balance
保持平衡
as you'll see when we get to it by the way that demonstration was a lot of fun
你会看到，当我们得到它的方式，示范是一个很大的乐趣
to do
做
now in talking about signals and systems as we go through the course
现在谈论信号与系统，因为我们经历的过程
their are several domains to in particular
他们有几个域，特别是
that we will find convenient for
我们会找到方便
the analysis and representation signals and systems
分析和表示信号与系统
one is the time-domain
1是时域
which is what we tend to think
这就是我们倾向于认为
and which we have kind of been focusing on
样的，我们一直专注于这
in the discussion so far in this lecture
在本次讲座的讨论至今
by equally important is what's referred to
通过同样重要的是什么的简称
as the frequency-domain
作为频域
as representation for signals
作为代表性的信号
and as a means for analysis for systems
和作为分析系统的装置
and in the context or the frequency-domain representation
并在上下文或频域表示
some old the kinds a ideas on topics that will be exploring
一些老种一个想法主题，将探讨
are the Fourier transform and
被傅里叶变换和
the le plus transform and
乐加变换和
a discrete-time counterpart the apostrophe is for which is the sea
离散时间对应的撇号是它是海
transport
运输
the Fourier transform discussion will get into fairly early in the course
傅里叶变换的讨论将进入在使用过程中相当早
and the La Paz transforming z transform
和拉巴斯转化Z变换
represent extensions the 48 transform and will be getting into
代表分机48变换，将进入
that later in the course just kinda initially
后来在使用过程中只是有点初步
to think about the time domain and frequency domain
思考的时域和频域
you might think for example over No being played
你可能会认为，例如在没有播放
and the time-domain representation would be
和时域表示法。将
how let's say the
怎么让我们说，
sound pressure as a function of time would change
声压与时间的函数将改变
and the frequency domain representation would
和频域表示将
correspond to representation the frequency content
对应表示的频率成分
the No and in fact what I'd like to do is
否，事实上我想要做的是什么
illustrate that and those two domain simultaneously
同时表明，与这两个领域
by playing a glockenspiel
打一个钟琴
no which'll here is the No
没有which'll这里是无
repeated several times over and at the same time
过，并在同一时间重复数次
you'll see to displays one on the left
你会看到，以显示一个在左边
representing the time domain display a representation
表示时间域显示一个表示
the signal and the one on the right representing the frequency
在表示频率的右信号和所述一个
me so let's look at that and
我所以让我们来看看这一点，
you'll hear the note and simultaneously see these two displays
你会听到的音符，同时看到这两个显示器
there's the No on the left time
有否在左边时
ways and on the right what we see
方式和我们所看到的权利
is frequency content in particular
是在特定的频率内容
indicating the fact dead there are several harmonics
指示该事实死有多个谐波
lines tell
线条诉说
okay well what I've gone thru
还好还有什么我已经走通
in this lecture represents a brief overview
在此讲学代表简要介绍
signals and systems and beginning with the next lecture we will be
信号与系统，并开始与下一讲中我们将
much more specific and precise first
更加具体和精确的第一
discussing some basic signals and then
讨论了一些基本的信号，然后
talking about systems and system properties and how to exploit
谈到系统和系统属性，以及如何利用
as one final comment that I'd
因为，我会最后一个评论
like to making this lecture I'd like to
喜欢做这个演讲，我想
emphasizes at the out said
强调在说出来
dead the taped lectures
死者的讲课录音
represent only one com- ponent the cores
代表只有一个com-分量的核心
and equally important will be
而同样重要的将是
both the textbook and the video course manual in particular
无论是教科书，特别是视频课程手册
it's important not only to reviewing the tapes
它不仅要检讨磁带重要
but simultaneously or in conjunction with that
但同时或在与该结合
doing the appropriate reading in the textbook and
做适当的阅读课本和
also working through the problems carefully
通过问题也正在仔细
in the video course manual in a course like this
在这样的过程中，视频课程手册
you basically only get out a bit as much as you put into it
你基本上只得到了一点因为你把它尽可能多
the hope is dead if you put the
如果你把希望死的
right amount of time and effort into it you'll find the course to be
你会发现过程是正确的时间和精力进去
educational and interesting and I certainly hope that will be the case
教育和有趣，我当然希望会是这样
thank you
谢谢